Ahmad **Obiedat**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Columbus, Ohio

□ 646-236-4991 | ☑ obiedatdeveloper@gmail.com | ☐ GitHub/obieda01 | ☐ ahmadobie

Summary

- Expert software engineer with 4+ years of hands-on web development background and significant Angular 4/7/8 project experience.
- Java Microservices Engineer with **3+** years of experience in application assessment and maintenance of Microservices architecture applications using Spring Boot, Spring Cloud config, and Restful Web Services.
- US Citizen: Authorized to work for any employer in the United States.

Skills

Fundamentals

Single-Page Web Apps | Scrum | Web Services APIs | Microservices | Systems Design | OOP | Data Structure | Testing | TDD | Databases | Cloud Computing | CI/CD | Machine Learning.

Coding

20000+ lines: Angular 4/7/8 | RxJS | Java | Spring Boot | JUnit | CSS | HTML | Bootstrap | Javascript | jQuery | SQL. **2000+ lines:** Bash | Git | TensorFlowJS | TensorFlow | Keras | Numpy | Pandas | Scikit-learn.

Experience __

• Nationwide Insurance - TEKsystems

Columbus OH

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan 2020 – Present

- Modernized three IBM WebSphere static web applications by replacing them with Angular 8. Resulted into 50% better throughput for our data heavy applications.
- Implemented Spring boot microservices using Spring Core, Spring MVC, Spring Cloud, Eureka, API Gateway, Hystrix, Zipkin, Sleuth, Hibernate, Restful services.
- Worked in agile framework, collaborating with business and research teams in story grooming, reviewing story/acceptance criteria and performance metrics.
- Worked in Test Driven Development (TDD) framework using JUnit.

• Accenture Columbus OH

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Apr 2019 – July 2019

• Designed, architected and wrote the front-end of our eCommerce application using Angular 5, RxJS with 400 reusable components. Achieved a Lighthouse score of 100/100.

• JPMorgan Chase & Co.

Columbus OH
May 2017 - Oct 2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Extensively worked with Angular 4+, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery.
- · Developed microservices using Java Spring Boot, Hibernate, Restful services with good quality of code.
- Participated in scrum meetings as part of iteration development process.

Education

• Tech Elevator - Java Spring Coding Bootcamp

2017 - 2017

• Jordan University of Science and Technology - B.Eng. in Computer Engineering

2005 - 2011

Personal Projects _

• 20+ Projects - Full Stack Development

Columbus OH

1 TO 3-PERSON(S) PROJECTS

2019 - present

- Implemented in Cloud GCP, C#, .Net Core, Java, Spring Boot, Microservices, Angular 8, RxJS, Typescript, Javascript, Git, HTML5, CSS3, REST APIs, SQL Server.
- Machine Learning projects: Build case studies in healthcare, autonomous driving, sign language reading, music generation, and natural language processing.

Certifications

• Google - Baseline: Data, ML, AI - Google Cloud Solutions II

2019 - 2020

• Udacity - Deep Learning Foundation Nanodegree Program

2018 - 2018

• Coursera - Deep Learning Specialization

2017 - 2018

AHMAD OBIEDAT · RÉSUMÉ